<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Pest Busters</string>

    <string-array name="pest">
        <item>Red_eared slider Turtle</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="guide"> Victorian bushlands provide food and habitat
        for the native animals. However, over the years,
        native animals are alarmingly endangering due to loss of habitat and attacked by
        exotic pest animals. At the same, the eco-logical balance is affected by
        the cause due to loss of biodiversity. These animals are found to be carrying
        exotic diseases to harm native and stock animals. For example, feral cats hunt
        a wide variety of animals from mammals, birds to reptiles. As per Victorian Australia,
        80 endangered species are at risk by feral cats itself. Additionally, another pest
        animal cane toad is also harmful for native frogs, reptiles, fish and mammals who
        consume almost everything they can swallow. </string>

     <string name="guide1">
         Except for the above mentioned, there are feral foxes, European rabbits,
         wild dogs and pigs many more. Government has been taking measures;
         however, the results are yet insignificant. Research further shows that the
         costs incurred by the Victorian Government due to these pests is approximated
         at $900 million each year making them a menace to the society. Therefore, Government is urging
         citizens to report the sighting of the pest animals for them to
         take appropriate measures.
     </string>

    <string name="guide2">Red eared slider turtle is a
        non-native animal recognized as a pest in Victoria.
        It is a classified as a priority pest animal in Victoria
        and the Government suspects that the red eared slider turtle
        to be a result of release from illegal pet trade, since turtles
        can live up to 50 years in the open and are their aggressive nature
        pose a threat to the native turtles more commonly found in the
        bushlands. The Red Eared Slider is also known to carry exotic
        diseases and need to be reported immediately if located. The pictures
        below can help you to recognize the turtle and its distinctive
        features and we urge the users to use our
        identify functions to recognize this priority pest with the highest accuracy</string>

</resources>



