<resources>
    <string name="app_name">InvasiPests</string>

    <string-array name="pest">
        <item>Red-eared Slider Turtle</item>
        <item>Canada Goose</item>
        <item>Goat</item>
        <item>Pigeon</item>
        <item>Rat</item>
        <item>Sparrow</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="guide"> Victorian bushlands provide food and habitat
        for the native animals. However, over the years,
        native animals are alarmingly endangering due to loss of habitat and attacked by
        exotic pest animals. At the same, the eco-logical balance is affected by
        the cause due to loss of biodiversity. These animals are found to be carrying
        exotic diseases to harm native and stock animals. For example, feral cats hunt
        a wide variety of animals from mammals, birds to reptiles. As per Victorian Australia,
        80 endangered species are at risk by feral cats itself. Additionally, another pest
        animal cane toad is also harmful for native frogs, reptiles, fish and mammals who
        consume almost everything they can swallow. </string>

    <string name="guide1">
         Except for the above mentioned, there are feral foxes, European rabbits,
         wild dogs and pigs many more. Government has been taking measures;
         however, the results are yet insignificant. Research further shows that the
         costs incurred by the Victorian Government due to these pests is approximated
         at $900 million each year making them a menace to the society. Therefore, Government is urging
         citizens to report the sighting of the pest animals for them to
         take appropriate measures.
     </string>

    <string name="guide2">Red eared slider turtle is a
        non-native animal recognized as a pest in Victoria.
        It is a classified as a priority pest animal in Victoria
        and the Government suspects that the red eared slider turtle
        to be a result of release from illegal pet trade, since turtles
        can live up to 50 years in the open and are their aggressive nature
        pose a threat to the native turtles more commonly found in the
        bushlands. The Red Eared Slider is also known to carry exotic
        diseases and need to be reported immediately if located. The pictures
        below can help you to recognize the turtle and its distinctive
        features and we urge the users to use our
        identify functions to recognize this priority pest with the highest accuracy</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="pest_menu">Pest Menu</string>
    <string name="red_eared_slider_turtle">Red-eared Slider Turtle</string>

    <string name="turlte_infor">Red-eared Slider Turtle, a controlled non-native pest animal in Victoria,
        originated from Sothern United States and Northern Mexico.
        They can be found mostly in the wild, where they tend to compete with native species.</string>

    <string name="turtlr_apperance">Medium sized, dark green
        colored with black and occasional yellow circular blotches
        of top shell (carapace). The bottom side (plastron) is bright
        yellow with black rings with blotches and swirls. They have a
        red or orange stripe in behind each eye and yellow stripes all over their body,
        congruent to their name.</string>

    <string name="turtle_risk">Red-eared Slider Turtle carries exotic diseases
        and parasitesas well asdue to their aggressive nature and high breeding
        rate can threaten native species</string>

    <string name="turtle_know">The sex of red-eared slider turtle
        can be determined by
        the temperature during development!</string>


    <string name="goat_infor">Feral goats, foreign pest in Australia, were introduced to supply meat and milk to the early setters, miners and construction teams. Due to accidental and deliberate releases now, they wildly populated across 35% of Australian land. Although, their distribution is rather unknown, they are mostly found in forested and
        semi-arid areas as well as sighted in regional and state parks and forests allover in Victoria.</string>

    <string name="goat_apperance">The goats have distinctive curved or corkscrew shaped horn to distinguish from other species, with some exception of hornless. They have long, short, silky hair with multi-colored coats.
        They have dangling fleshy lobes around their necks and tend to have straight or rounded noses.</string>

    <string name="goat_risk">Feral goats are prone to exotic diseases (Q fever, tetanus, rabies, foot &amp; moth diseases) and tend to be carrier in transferring the diseases to domestic sheep and goat herds.
        They damage vegetation by overgrazing to prevent regeneration and soil erosion.</string>

    <string name="goat_know">Goats can stand and take their first steps within minutes of being born!</string>


    <string name="goose_infor">Canada goose, a non-native pest in Australia, can be found in semi-deserts, forests, coastal areas, wetlands,
        lakes and agricultural land.  They adversely affect agriculture, environment and human health.</string>

    <string name="goose_apperance">Medium to large sized with brown and white with. In addition, they have long black neck and head with black bill, tail, legs and feet. Their distinctive
        features are white patches on their cheeks and chins and V-shaped white marks on the ramps.</string>

    <string name="goose_risk">They droppings contain harmful diseases and bacteria harming both human and native waterfowl species. In addition, they compete with native species for food and nesting sites.
        They foul and trample gardens, lawns, pathways and so on.</string>

    <string name="goose_know">Canada goose have caused many serious aeroplane crashes while flying near airports! </string>

    <string name="myna_infor">Indian Myna, a member native to Asia, is considered as one of the world’s most invasive species, posing serious threat to agriculture, human and biodiversity.
        They can be found in Coastal regions as well as in humanized urban areas.</string>

    <string name="myna_apperance">Indian Myna can be identified for their distinctive yellow beak and patch behind the eyes.
        They have brown body with black hooded head and bright yellow bill and legs.</string>

    <string name="myna_risk">Being omnivorous, Indian myna survives on insects, reptiles, small mammal, grains, fruits and seeds. Their aggressive behavior towards chicks of other native birds and their habitat is why they are considered invasive species.
        Their scavenging nature is particularly a problem in Australia. </string>

    <string name="myna_know">Indian myna is named as flying rats and cane toad of the sky because of their notoriety!</string>

    <string name="pigeon_infor">Pigeons, originally inhabited from ancestors in Europe, is increasingly common in urban areas of Australia in search of food and habitats.
        Vacant buildings, and structural defects are attractive roosting sites for them.</string>

    <string name="pigeon_apperance">Pigeons have a blue-grey with a mix of white ramp and two blacks
        bars across their wings, with a dark band around the end of their tails.</string>

    <string name="pigeon_risk">In addition to carrying disease and parasites, they tend to damage to industrial, domestic and commercial buildings by breeding and nesting in roof spaces. Pigeons droppings cause damage to agriculture by introducing
        weeds and diseases as well as presence of corrosive acid in the droppings damages buildings and monuments.  </string>

    <string name="pigeon_know">In addition to carrying disease and parasites, they tend to damage to industrial, domestic and commercial buildings by breeding and nesting in roof spaces.
        Pigeons droppings cause damage to agriculture by introducing weeds and diseases
        as well as presence of corrosive acid in the droppings damages buildings and monuments. </string>

    <string name="about_1">
        Exotic pests in Victorian Bushland pose major threats to biodiversity, environment and agriculture
        and human lives. However, Government is unable to locate the animals due to their invasive nature.
    </string>

    <string name="about_2">
        Our mission is to join Victorian Government in controlling the havoc, by identifying and locating these pest animals accurately. But we cannot do this alone. We strongly believe
        that together we thrive, alone we perish - lend us a hand in maintaining the eco-logical balance.
    </string>

    <string name="about_3">
       Please make sure to maintain safe distance from dangerous animals
    </string>

    <string name="guide_ar">
        Pests Archive contains information about the priority and top invasive
        pests in Victoria. It includes general introduction to their habitat,
        appearance, and risk factors. You may use the information to learn about pest animals
        to manually identify them, or else use the
        identify feature of our application to detect with higher accuracy.
    </string>

    <string name="guide_loca">Find locations of pest animals in the application map and
        take safety measures while visiting these areas</string>

    <string name="report_1">
Find previous reports sent in this section.
        Select any of the pest animals to see the number of pest animals sighted by other people in a bar graph.
    </string>

    <string name="report_2">
You can also get the postcodes of
        the location and analyze the percentage of pest animals in certain areas for a quick browse (in a pie chart).
    </string>



    <!--Stralings-->

    <string name="str_infor">
Common Starlings, alternately called as the European starlings, native to Eurasia, is widespread around
        Australia to-date. They generally low land birds, commonly found in non-mountainous areas.
    </string>

    <string name="str_app">
        Common starlings have long and glossy back feathers with a metallic glaze.
        The bleak of the bird varies with season; black in winter and yellow in summer with pink legs.
    </string>

    <string name="str_risk">
        Common starlings are hosts to many parasites, including externally carrying fleas, mites, ticks and around 95% carry internal parasites such as worms. They feed on sprouting crops, grains and fruits, and causes harm to the agricultural fields, livestock facilities and contaminating human food sources with their droppings. Their predatory natures and natural
        tendency to coexist with human are what causing of native social birds like woodpecker decline.
    </string>

    <string name="str_know">
        Common starlings
        can mimic human speeches and car alarms and gained attention for evolution of human language researches!
    </string>


    <!--sparrow-->
    <string name="spa_infor">
        Of the 25 species found in most parts of the world, house sparrows
        are native to Europe. They tend to live around human habitats, leaving woodlands and desert areas.
    </string>

    <string name="spa_app">
      House sparrows are small birds with varied appearance based on their sex. Females have colored pale brown and grey and males have brighter black, brown and white markings on their head,
        a reddish back and grey underprints. Males have a distinctive crown on top of its bill to back.
    </string>

    <string name="spa_risk">
    House sparrows are aggressive by nature and compete for nesting sites and kill other birds including their hatchlings and eggs. They drive native birds away by taking over the food sources. At the same time, they also invade human houses and food factories and not only
        make a nuisance by building nests, but also carry diseases and contaminate foods.
    </string>

    <string name="spa_know">
      House sparrows aren’t water birds; however, they can actually swim underwater to escape traps or predators!
    </string>

    <!--rat-->

    <string name="rat_infor">
       Black rat, originating from Indian subcontinent, are common long tailed rodents. This is considered as a serious pest, as being
        omnivores, they feed on seeds, leaves, fruits, and wide range of invertebrates and vertebrates.
    </string>

    <string name="rat_app">
        Black rat has several forms of color, commonly with black or grey-brown furry coats and black to light brown color
        in the bottom. Their smaller body and larger eyes and ears are distinguishable from brown rats.
    </string>

    <string name="rat_risk">
     The intense damages caused to plantations may take years to reverse as they reduce pH of soils and nutrients availability while feeding on them and restrict plant germination. Their generalist mentality in food preferences cause rapid decline and extinction to native species such as snails, bush rat and so on. They are even capable
        of passing disease causing bacteria and viruses to human, in some cases which are incurable.
    </string>

    <string name="rat_know">
       Next time you hear a high-pitched noise from a rat, know that they are laughing during their play-time!
    </string>




</resources>



